Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer Tallinn, Estonia +372 511 1618 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

PROFILE

I have eight years of experience as a software developer, with a focus on Java. I commit to teamwork, building applications that undergo rigorous testing and seamless delivery. I love researching and staying updated with the latest technologies. I'm always searching for ways to improve my skills and make my work better.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Programming Languages: Java, TypeScript, Python Hibernate, Junit, Mockito, WireMock **Technologies:** Spring Boot, Angular, Vue,

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis Languages: English, Estonian, Russian

EXPERIENCE

• Bankera Tallinn, Estonia
Senior Software Engineer Jun 2022 - Present

• In my position on the Know Your Customer (KYC) team, I led the creation and upkeep of microservices using Spring Boot and Java (from versions 8 to 21). I used databases like Postgres and testing tools including Mockito, Wiremock, and Assert J. My work helped build strong, scalable, and effective solutions for complying

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia

 $Technical\ Lead\ Engineer$

Technical Lead Engineer

with financial services regulations.

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

- As a part of the Payments team, I was leading and refactoring a monolith into a single responsibility microservice.
- $\circ~$ I was in charge of architecting a strong customer authentication (SCA PSD2) solution.

• Monese

London, United Kingdom

Jul 2020 - Sep 2021

• Reduced costs by systematically improving software performance and decreasing operating costs. For one application, its monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.

• Monese

London, United Kingdom

 $Software\ Engineer$

Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

- Increased revenue by identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a solution for a single customer led to the identification of a significant gap in profit.
- As a part of the Pricing team, delivered business priorities by completing a new, annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues. Additionally, I led research on breaking a monolithic application into a single responsibility microservice.
- As a part of the Joint Accounts team, I designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia

Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- As a part of the Smart Transactions team, I improved the scalability of micro-services by separating the read and write operation of the database.
- \circ Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. As a result, the average response time decreased from 60ms to 5ms.
- Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- \circ As a part of the Recurring Payments team, I designed and developed a micro-service with a test coverage of up to 80%.

• Codeborne

Software Developer

Tallinn, Estonia

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

• As a part of the Banking team, I advocated for clean, robust, and maintainable code while promoting through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.

- Increased the team's productivity by sharing my peers' development tricks.
- o Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.

• Knowit
Software Developer
Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Employee of the Q4, 2016.
- Developed a full-stack, web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.

EDUCATION

• Tartu University Estonia

Master of Engineering (MEng); Computer Science; GPA: 4.67/5;

- o Master's Thesis "Developing a Web-Based Mini-Mental State Examination: Innovations in Accessibility and Efficiency for Cognitive Assessment"
- \circ Achievement stipend
- o Specialisation stipend

• Tallinn University Estonia

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc); Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

- o Bachelor's Thesis "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot"
- Achievement stipend
- \circ Specialisation stipend